Guide to the Events Reference Collection, 1903-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Events Reference collection 1903-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
1.3 linear feet Extent: approx. 1,300 Items
The Events Reference Collection contains files of clippings, programs, brochures, and other materials concerning various academic, professional, and social events at the University. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
UA.01.11.0069
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Events Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Collection Overview
The collection contains materials pertaining to celebrations, exhibits, conferences, symposia, lectures, meetings, visitors, and other events such as Parents' Weekend, the British-American Festival, and seasonal celebrations. Information about campus events will be found also in the records of sponsoring bodies, such as the Duke University Union, and academic departments and divisions.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Social life and customs; British American Festival (1984: Durham, N.C.)
Related Material
Calendar of Duke University, 1930-1966
Duke University Archives
Duke University Calendar, 1966-1985
Duke University Archives
Commencement Collection, 1850-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Convocations Collection, 1937-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Duke University Union Records, 1954-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Founders’ Day Collection, 1903-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) Reference Collection, 1892-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Preliminary Description of Collection
- Container List
  - All-campus carnival, 1980 (Box 1)
  - American Historical Association meeting, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Biblical colloquium, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Blackburn Literary Festival, circa 1970- (Box 1)
  - British-American Festival, 1984 - brochures (Box 1)
  - British-American Festival, 1984 - clippings (Box 1)
  - Conference of Corporate Chief Executive Officers, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Conference for Secondary School Counselors, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - Conference for Teachers of Social Studies, 1955-1968 (Box 1)
  - Conference on International Legal Studies, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Consortium on Revolutionary Europe, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Council for the Advancement of Science Writing, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Dante Centenary, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls, 1950- (Box 1)
  - Duke Plays, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Duke-UNC Slavic Colloquium, 1962-1968 (Box 1)
  - Fashion Seminar, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Flagpole ceremony at the start and end of the academic year, 1903- (Box 1)
  - Forum on Democracy, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Forum on Presidential Nominations, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Hispanic Scholars Conference, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Holiday tree-lighting ceremony, circa 1973- (Box 1)
  - Homecoming, circa 1935- (Box 2)
  - Inter-American Institute of the University of North Carolina, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Institute of International Relations, 1931-1938 (Box 2)
  - Joe College, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Laboratory Conference for Teachers of Science and Mathematics, 1952-1964 (Box 2)
  - Lectures
    - Anthony Joseph Drexel Biddle, Jr. Lecture on International Studies, 2000- (Box 2)
    - Camille and Henry Dreyfus Distinguished Scholar, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Benjamin N. Duke, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    - Fritz London Lectures, 1976- (Box 2)
    - Henry W. Newsom Memorial, 1980- (Box 2)
    - John Jay Gergen Memorial Lecture, 1977, 1985 (Box 2)
    - John McTyeire Flowers, 1923, 1927 (Box 2)
    - Robert Lee Patterson Lecture in Philosophy, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Terry Sanford Distinguished, 1989- (Box 2)
  - Management Day, 1987 (Box 2)
  - May Day Pageant, circa 1924-1967 (Box 2)
  - National Resources Conference, Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1954 (Box 2)
  - National Security Policy Seminar, Duke-UNC, 1961-1965 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina
    - Council of Teachers of English meeting, 1925 (Box 2)
    - Education Association, 1937, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Federal Personnel Management Council Conference, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Junior Science Symposium, 1958-1962 (Box 2)
    - Press Association institutes, circa 1933-1994 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Parents' Weekend, 1974- (Box 3)
  - Parents' Weekend, brochures, 1975- (Box 3)
  - Peace Science Society meeting, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Regional Assembly, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Scavenger hunts, 1989- (Box 3)
  - School of Law Conference, 1954-1969 (Box 3)
  - September 11, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Southeastern Personnel Conference, 1948-1954 (Box 3)
  - Southern Newspaper Publishers Association, 1969, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Student Institute of World Affairs, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Summer Science and Mathematics Institute, 1957-1960 (Box 3)
  - Symposia
    - Commonwealth of Children, 1962 (Box 3)
    - International Relations and World Affairs, 1970- (Box 3)
    - Oak Ridge Regional, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Visitors
    - General, 1896- (Box 3)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt, 1934- (Box 3)
    - Viscount Halifax, 1943 (Box 3)
    - Eric Johnston, 1944 (Box 3)
  - Washington Bicentennial Celebration, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Woman's College Anniversary Celebration, 2002 (Box 3)